[Music]
hello hello cave it's Frank defus hello
Frank how are you fine you okay things
looking a little better for you now yeah
things are absolutely fine now so that's
great I'm glad we we made contact yeah
I'm I'm I'm glad you agreed to come on
to the show I'm sure uh the listeners
will be very interested in hearing what
you have to say thank you very much why
don't you start off by telling people a
little bit about your background in
holography background in holography
um I started um I studied physics at
London University okay and I became
interested in holography when I saw the
um the shows at the Royal Academy of
Arts in London and this is
around um 1978 that sort of time okay
that's that's that's pretty early this
is pretty I'm showing my age here now
these were really quite incredible shows
for those who haven't seen it they
really you know anyone who didn't see it
or wasn't around wasn't old enough that
really missed the greatest shows of
holography ever and these were by uh
Nick Phillips's group at lury University
okay and they really were quite
fantastic huge Holograms that's when I
really got
interested in holography um as it
happens um Imperial College where I was
studying physics it has a very good
Optics department and
and partly because of this interest I
went to study um um
Optics and got a master's degree there
and then I went on to do holography
too um as a PhD project wow where
specifically uh display holography mhm
yeah and what university this is this is
London University which is divided into
colleges um because this is a big
college it's known as it sort of it's
known as Imperial College mhm oh okay
yes yes yes this which is incidentally
coincidentally where gor discovered
yes um so that's that's how I started
and it's one of these things when you
when you get the holography bug as you
probably know it it it doesn't leave you
no it does
not so ever since then um uh just to go
on with the story I did my PhD in
holography then I got involved in um in
a company called icon
holographics okay where we were trying
to uh make Holograms more
um uh more
marketable um that's a real challenge
isn't it this is it yeah this is this is
this is the Big Challenge over the years
and I worked on a viewer um for for
Holograms based on dispersion
compensation that basically made it easy
did the view Holograms mhm sort of plug
and
play um and I also did work on color
holography which I was very interested
in uh to for for obvious reasons really
yeah but that's a sort of basic uh
introduction and and what are you doing
what's your what's your projects right
now what are you doing now not too much
in holography I'm I mean uh about what
15 years ago I moved aside and I started
a company in the publishing area or type
setting uh so that's continued and
that's become a sort of established
company for um working for Publishers
yeah that that that's a field that's
gone through quite a transition too yeah
which is what keeps it interesting for
me yeah is part of the reason I went I
again I got interested in that when I
started when I saw the Apple Macintosh
first yes when it first came out I got
one of the first series and
um than again showing my uh my longevity
or my age here and that you know I got
got in touch with Publishers who who who
couldn't understand how you could draw
illustrations using a computer and I one
or two of them they succumbed and of
course Everything's changed since then
yeah so right now that's my day job if
you like now last few years it's uh
because it's been established and I've
got some colleagues who work with me
I've got more time on my hands so I uh
I've I've uh thankfully I've been able
to spend a bit more time on on
holography so I'm doing nothing
practical on holography but a lot of
thinking and theoretical and and uh just
I I I
still do hope one day to do uh a lot
more work in holography again and I'm
I'm working on that well I guess that
was just a natural way of getting into
the website that you have holograph
for.org which is basically I believe
it's set up to be online public for
holography yes
now I thought this is the one thing I
can do because uh we are we are uh what
we do every day is is to take papers
from authors and and convert them into u
a form to be types set to be searchable
Etc and that's that's our business and I
thought well that's where perhaps I can
contribute um and the idea was to have a
site where people anyone can send an
article yes um and we would put it into
shape and put it into HTML and and and
PDF what have you um and uh upload it
and it's at least up to now it's all
completely free of charge yes yes um let
me ask you this as a
typographer uh by the way which I love
typography and uh I often go into New
York well not often but at one time when
I was younger I'd go into New York just
to see EX at the international typ face
Corporation okay ITC and my my youngest
daughter's middle name I named her after
a famous typographer from Italy Aldo
novice so her middle name is novice
which is a type face but this this goes
back back to the uh quite a few years
ago but do you find the web frust as
someone who's a typographer which is
basically a fine art in in many senses
because your choice of typ face and what
that type face is trying to convey along
with the message has to match very well
do you find the web be quite frustrating
to uh work with type
faes in its limitations okay I I have to
admit here I'm not very good at HTML I
don't that's sort of a ho in my
knowledge that I don't know how HTML how
it chooses fonts yeah Etc um well the
the thing with a web page is the fact
that uh there are so many fonts to
choose from and there are only so many
fonts that are loaded on someone's
computer and if uh if you happen to have
designed a document that contains
certain fonts you put it into HTML on a
and the person goes to the web page if
they don't have that typ face their
browser just defaults to whatever face
they have set so you know you may have a
very beautiful uh type type typography
on your document but to that person all
their seeings it's like times
Roman yes I I can understand and
actually you can change also you can
change your preference you I like this
font or that font so I suppose the the
that the the web really isn't it really
isn't a good good medium at the moment
to to read things mhm uh in you know
long passages because it really doesn't
have any typography yeah you have no
control um that's interesting because I
was I was at a um one of our clients is
is nature nature publishing group who
published a bit the nature Journal mhm
and they were saying that they find that
most people they they put up their their
documents in HTML and in PDF yes PDF
yeah yeah and they find that most people
by far they're not interested in reading
the the HTML they might go through it
but then they click and download the PDF
yes and either read that on screen or
print it out and read it m so people
still prefer that that the PDF which
allows you to have control over that the
the little nuances of uh uh hyphenation
or page breaks and and and and type yeah
so I agree that's a limitation I have I
have filing cabinets that are just
filled with documents over the past I
guess maybe 30 years in holography I
mean I have issues of holosphere that go
back before even the Museum of
holography took over the publication oh
they're they're all in plastic you know
they're all in plastic sleeves archival
plastic
sleeves and um I've I've thought so many
times just to go through everything and
and put an online reading Library
together but I guess when you get into
copyrights and who owns this and who
owns that I guess uh you just can't go
ahead and do something like that go
ahead and do it now there's a lot of now
Google is doing a bit which is something
is quite contr yeah I just read about
that yeah putting books online um it it
would be so great and holosphere is a
good example I actually two three years
ago I actually wrote or sent an email to
the MIT Museum of holography who had
taken over everything the Museum of
holography including holosphere oh I see
and they have copies of all of these and
I said you know would you allow me to to
scan these and put them up for free on
my website which is exactly what you're
saying yeah unfortunately I got an email
saying um from the you know legal
department saying No this is a you you
can't do that but we may allow you to
put a table of contents or something
like that oh I see um you know copyright
has uh it's it's good and uh and and and
bad at the same time yeah yeah so but I
wish there's so much information on
there oh and there are so many
newsletters like wfront is another one
that I have
of and there were actually U quite a few
uh periodical type of they not regularly
public published uh in Europe but uh
there were quite a few people who had uh
European uh holographic Publications as
well that I have full copies of really
oh that would be it would be great to um
to have those available in in some way
yeah and also H um holographics
International yes the color magazine
that Sonny Baines was doing yes and I
don't know if you remember or not but
there was a publication out of Petaluma
California from uh Jeffrey Murray and uh
Patty pink I believe at the time called
laser news yeah yep yep yeah all of them
oh that's that's really I wish I I had
all of them but uh I think we should uh
yeah we we we should work on that and
make them available in in in some way
yeah but I'm sure that if we um there's
actually been some discussion on the
this The Forum holography Forum yes last
few days about
holosphere so maybe um maybe they will
succumb if we if we follow it up yeah
it's possible it's possible and I think
what happens a lot of time with
holography is uh the fact that people
who are working in the field are
holographs they're not
writers and it's tough to get a u a
constant supply of any type of uh
Publications I guess outside of the fact
you know like spie or back with the old
holography uh symposiums at Lake Forest
I mean at those times people submit
papers but just to keep a periodical
going I imagine it's very difficult
because people make Holograms they're
not uh
writers uh correct correct yes
[Music]
um you're you're right and and uh really
I well what you're doing now of course
this is keeping a video an audio record
yes and that's something which you which
you can't people you can't write down MH
um and and video perhaps a multimedia
and I think that you know new
technologies coming are going to change
the publishing world really drastically
things like the iPod iPod video for
example that's just come out and that's
I think that's a great way of of having
information with you all the time yes
I'm I'm very concerned about how this
iPod video is going to affect bandwidth
you know we all share bandwidth and you
know downloading a web page or
downloading a picture is one thing but
uh when you start downloading 1eh hour
episodes of television shows every week
and you've got so many people doing it
what's going to happen to the bandwidth
uh yes good point um I I don't know I
don't know either um you'd be surprised
how many people tune into this show that
are still on 56k dialup modems sure and
a few in Europe are still on 144 really
yes and uh forget those people oh we
must that that's why I try to keep the U
the bit rate as low as possible I mean I
I could put up very high quality files
and uh of course people with high
bandwidth would have access to them with
no problem but anybody who's 56k or 144
forget about it well I it's it's a good
question and and I don't know what um
what the the what what is happening
whether the you know new systems are
going to keep up I mean I expect someone
there is is thinking about this you know
yeah um again
yes I'm actually going to have Hol talk
available and I'll let the listeners
know this through America Online where
the show will also be stored on America
online servers okay so that uh I I
believe that's sent out to many
different parts of the world so when you
come to the holot talk page if you just
choose the um the AOL uh server link
you'll be able to get a local copy of
the show from your country I
believe okay so would you say you have
your finger on the pulse of holography
there in England and if you do uh what
seems to be going
on I suppose the short answer the two
two two two word answer must be not
much um or or I don't have the finger
it's more than it was um you've got
you've got the few Die Hard um you've
got let me see now well for me I suppose
um Rob Monday of Monday special
Imaging um he's continued over the years
um and they
have uh they've just started a um as you
know they they've started um teaching
holography I think the last show wasn't
it yeah we uh Patrick boy I
believe uh that sounds good and and it
sounds like you know they're busy now I
think that's quite significant because
we haven't really had there are not many
places where you can go and learn
holography yes so I'm hopefully that
will continue mhm
um I'm looking forward to this
conference that uh Hans SP is is is
organizing in Wales that's next next
July oh I wish I could come to that yeah
I wish to I would love to do broadcasts
from
there yes you know well I'm I'm sort of
thinking of of doing something something
either a video or some sort of
multimedia recording yes really we
should we should record these things for
oh absolutely even if it's not if it's
not live for posterity oh sure
absolutely so I'll I'll see what I can
do but uh uh don't tell anyone well I
hav't told anyone until now you just
told the world my friend know I know I
realized
that do you want me to do you want me to
edit that out no no no no that's all I'm
saying I'm I'm thinking about it if
anyone there wants to give me a hand uh
you know give give me a send me an email
because I I think things should be uh
I'm thinking you know video audio
multimedia and all linked Poss if if
possible linked to the proceedings PF to
you know real multimedia that's well you
know one of my ideas one of my ideas was
that I mean you can never take place of
people assembling together and human
interaction I mean that that has value
in and of itself regardless but it's
it's not necessary anymore for people to
travel to a specific location in order
to have a conference yeah you could
contact everyone who's supplying
materials and put those multimedia
presentations on the web and then have
the entire conference web-based there's
no reason to actually have have a
physical location for everyone to travel
to anymore absolutely right well there
are two things one is having a live
conference you know people talking at
the asking questions yeah that's of
course that's a different that's sort of
webcasting Live Well actually that could
be worked out too it would it would be
post uh post uh the conference online
but you could have people come back
online at a specific date say for
instance the whole conference goes up
online uh July 1st and then you would
say okay starting uh July 17th this
person will be available online live
starting uh the 23rd this person would
be available I mean there's different
ways of working it there are different
way but I 100% I agree with you 100 and
that is actually my my
present pet project at the moment is I'm
actually telling my colleagues my
Publishers who we work for our the the
our clients if you like what I'm saying
is guys you know please let's let's
firstly get away from this idea that a
publication is a piece of paper or even
a PDF file or HTML MH you can have
different kinds of media and also we can
we if the supposing you Frank you can't
supposing you can't I hope you can come
to the conference but if you can't then
it shouldn't be the case that you've
just lost out you've just you know
you've you've you've you've lost
everything that that that was talked at
at the conference yes
um and you just have to wait for the
proceedings yes we can wait for
proceedings but you know artists for
example they they they they they they
don't want to be bothered to write and
even scientists they might speak better
than they write you what you really want
is to to feel you're there so you should
be able to later you say well I can't go
to this conference but that's fine I can
look at it online that's should be as
you say well you know a lot of times
with the people who have the conferences
and I have found this personally with uh
large Fields rather than holography
which is still relatively a small field
compared to something uh similar to
health care or medicine or something
like that is that the people who are
holding the conference they don't want
to give people the option of not
attending because number one they have
they usually have some sort of a trade
show that goes along with it the only
way that they can get companies there to
exhibit at the trade show is to say this
is how many X number of people we're
going to have here at this event uh they
need people there and they will turn
their nose up and and and dismiss the
fact that it could be they know that it
can be done online but it hurts them to
do it because if someone's in uh another
area of the country or outside of the
country they'll say well why should I
attend that I'll just stay here and wait
for it to go online even if I have to
register and pay for it online I can sit
here in my pajamas and listen to it why
do I need to be there and that's that's
one of the downfalls according to you
know looking at it Playing devil's
advocate and looking at it from the side
of the person who's holding the
conference yeah yeah it I understand
well actually I don't understand that
because I think that's a you know it's a
negative kind of reason and negative re
reasons are not are never good reasons
oh yeah yeah but it's out there I think
this it reminds me of if you look back
in history for example When U the you
know the gramophone record was first
invented there was a lot of resistance
to you know making gramophone records
available to to you know every Tom Dick
and Harry yeah because people wouldn't
go to concerts mhm and when television
came along that actually there was
resistance because Cinemas thought
they'd lose but in every case yes they
found a way increased yes the number of
attendees and I think this will do the
same because people you watch two
conferences and you say look this looks
like a great show I wish I was there to
ask him this question or that question
so you give people a flavor of what it's
like to be there so I think I I think
it'll change there's you know resistance
but um it it it'll have to happen
because it it just has to now holograph
for.org is actually a sponsor of this
conference is that correct do you want
to speak a little bit about Your
sponsorship of it um it's yes what we've
done basically I spoke we spoke with
Hans and I was interested in really it's
it's a long time since we had a um
holography conference um specifically
for display holography so I guess it was
what six years ago
um and I really want to make this a help
make this a big show although I'm not
the organizer um we are going to help
with the with the proceedings what we
want to do is to make a really a nice
set of proceedings I see um we haven't
worked the details out but we'll try and
my company because we we are you know in
this game we'll make them look nice and
and be types set as opposed to the
normal kind of proceedings where you get
uh just you know a cam ready copy of
whatever the author gives I see um
that's one thing um we haven't worked at
other things but basically I'm I'm we
are going to be uh helping out the
little things and again I'm hoping to do
this uh this multimedia recording if it
works out now that I've told everyone um
I might have to do it um so there's
there's no more real details at the
moment but closer to time um I'm sure
there'll be little things that we
do um to to get as many people there and
hopefully make this a another kind of
stepping stone or or try and uh uh um
get a new generation in interested in
holography and an important thing is
that Jonathan Ross is going to have I
think hopefully he's going to have a
good collectioned there uh um and you
know not many people see shows of really
first class uh Holograms these days MH
um now will the will the proceedings be
available
online uh they will be available that
again I'm not sure and I haven't it's
it's not really my decision yeah but
they'll certainly be available
electronically um I think an idea is
that they might be available
electronically and you can have a print
version if you want something along
those lines yeah yeah but we do want
them to be you know really
electronically available so in future
you can you can search them for keywords
Etc yeah
exactly well since we're coming up on 25
minutes is there anything that uh we
didn't cover that you would like to
cover well I'm I'm aware that we we
didn't talk much
holography yeah well there's there's
this is an aspect of holography so uh
right it's it's a different type of show
but uh what what is it that you'd like
to talk about specifically um let me
think really my my I'm I'm I'm still
very very optimistic uh we we
really my view is that holography or
display holography as as as as we know
it um is is not used enough it is it's
not regarded highly enough and
we have to do something to change that
there are too many Holograms low quality
cheap Holograms around they look cheap
and they are cheap mhm um and I still
have a lot of uh uh really I'm
optimistic about the future of
holography that perhaps in the next two
or 3 years we we can change things and
get a few more people interested mhm um
you
know so that's a tall that's a tall
order and the only reason why I say that
is that gez I my first holography show
was 1976 in Philadelphia through the
Looking Glass when the Museum of
holography was on tour and uh basically
same thing
then yeah but you know you have to when
you bu I think if you believe in
something I really I really believe if
if we
have the problem these days is people
just don't see we have at least one
generation well say one generation who
really hasn't seen a good first quality
hologram yeah we used to have in London
I mean we used to have the say for
example the light fantastic Gallery in
Coven Garden which you could just go
into any time and there were at least
two or three absolutely breathtaking
Holograms mhm you know I if I hadn't
seen some some of those Holograms in the
early days I wouldn't have come into the
field yeah if I'd seen the Holograms I
see around toy shops now well yeah you
know you can't blame people for not
being interested yeah so let's uh well I
am optimistic and um let's um let's
let's see what we can do I'm optimistic
for the amateurs and the hobbyists I
think that I think that the uh work
that's going to come out of some of the
work that's taking place with some of
the amateur and hobbyist holographs is
what's going to throw this over the
line right I really do something's going
to happen and uh it's it's very slow
it's a very slow ground swell but it's
uh it's some of the most interesting
stuff that's going on in holography
right now I think I think so yeah it's
very interesting what's happening in uh
in basements and garages not only in
this country but around the world and
the experiments that people are doing
the sharing of the information through
the uh fors that are online it's um it's
uh a ground
swell well let's let's let's hope it
continues um and of course with the new
cheaper lasers that makes things a lot
easier doesn't it it certainly does um
you know
um yeah I remember getting my first
laser and what I had to go through to
pay for that every month you know it was
something yeah well I want to thank you
very much for being on the show any last
words you'd like to throw in there as we
come up on a half hour program not
really just to thank you for uh for for
for thinking of me and hope uh hope
there's something in this that that
interest people and uh I really do hope
you can uh make it make it to this
conference and we can we can meet after
many years of knowing about each other
yeah that would be something there's
there's so many so many people that uh
you know I'm just in a small town in
Pennsylvania and uh that's where I've
always been and uh it would be before
before I pass on to the afterlife I
would love to uh at least shake hands or
give a hug or whatever to so many people
that have been a part of my life since
oh my goodness I started reading about
holography back in ' 68 so you know I
was just a kid yeah you know well we'll
we'll uh we'll we'll see if we can come
over there and give you a hug
instead all right well thank you and
website again is holograph for.org and
there'll be a link on the website to go
right over there and you're always
looking for new papers and new
Publications from folks are please if
anyone this yes this is I should have
said this um I started this must be
quite a while ago maybe two years ago I
started holograph for.org um it's it's
for anyone who can write anything and
you can go there and look at the
different
categories um that is of use to to
holographs please give me a just click
on the link there and let's uh keep it
going now is there is there a specific
format that you want people to send them
to do you want them already converted to
PDF or do you do that it's all on there
it's all on there and also I have some
some some general guidelines as to how
to write I'm not looking for these are
not papers these are not this is not
pompous papers with the with you know
big words yeah this is this is it must
be clear it must
be understandable but in good clean
everyday English great um so uh yes that
would be it would be great to uh to have
some
submissions okay well thank you very
much thank you very much Frank all right
take care bye by
bye